Colin L. Z. Schoeneman

631 Brandi Ln, Lawrenceville, GA 30044 colin.schoeneman@gmail.com 770-851-2361

Current part-time UX/UI Design student. Experienced IT business consulting professional and team leader specializing in CRM implementations and IT modernization. Certified Salesforce practitioner (Administrator and Platform App Builder). Experience leading high-performing agile teams as a Scrum Master and Functional Lead. Specializes in systems analysis, requirements gathering, user story development, and testing. Experience in the finance, transportation, and healthcare industries.

EXPERIENCE

Deloitte ConsultingSenior Consultant, Technology Consulting

Arlington, VA

October 2015 to November 2019

CLIENT: Consumer Financial Protection Bureau | ROLE: Agile Scrum Master/Functional Team Lead (Aug 2017 to Nov 2019)

- Supported the ongoing enhancement and maintenance of a large Salesforce case management solution that supports the intake of complaints from consumers and routes them to companies for responses
- Served as the Scrum Master and led daily scrum calls with internal development team and clients (15-20 people total)
- Served as functional team lead managing 3 junior practitioners in requirements gathering, user story creation, and testing
- Led and supported requirements gathering meetings with key business stakeholders. Understood and internalized client business processes and informed the technical team on behalf of the client
- Led weekly prioritization meetings with business stakeholders and groomed an extensive enhancements backlog
- Drafted and refined system requirements in the form of functional user stories. Worked with business stakeholders and the development team to answer questions and develop detailed, consumable requirements
- Led solutioning meetings with the development team utilized knowledge of the Salesforce platform and CFPB's business processes combined with analytical thinking to support discussions and recommend implementation solutions
- Wrote and executed detailed test scripts for unit, regression, smoke, and user acceptance testing (UAT)
- Prepared and executed detailed functionality demos for stakeholders
- Prepared UAT test scripts, facilitated UAT sessions with key stakeholders, and collected and reported on feedback received

CLIENT: Amtrak | ROLE: Functional Analyst (Dec 2015 to Jul 2017)

- Supported IT modernization efforts to replace legacy labor management and train scheduling systems
- Performed daily unit testing, end-to-end systems integration testing, and regular regression testing on iterative builds of the labor management and train scheduling solutions
- Served as testing lead and developed and maintained hundreds of test cases in the project's HP-ALM suite
- Served as defect manager reviewed all incoming defects from a team of 15 testers for quality and completeness, facilitated communication and solutioning with developers regarding defects, and retested all defect fixes
- Led client UAT sessions side-by-side with clients that were crucial to increase familiarity and buy-in to the software and to ultimately close out the testing phase of the project

MAXIMUS, Inc. Reston, VA

Analyst, Business Systems

January 2013 to October 2015

- Consulted with health government clients in the state of the New York to provide the systems solutions to support existing and new programs for the largest state-run public healthcare system in the nation
- Gathered business requirements from the operations team and translated those into technical requirements to guide development
- Refined technical problem-solving skills, used them to find root cause of software bugs and to devise implementation solutions
- Created test sets and performed extensive Quality Assurance testing for bug fixes and improvement/new feature implementations
- Used SQL to query, analyze, and report on production data to meet time-intensive data requests from operations and state clients
- Provided daily support to call center operations to help troubleshoot and resolve production issues
- Put Capability Maturity Model Integration (CMMI) Level 3 processes into practice and participated in CMMI artifact creation

American Cancer Society
Atlanta, Georgia

Search Marketing Intern

February 2011 to July 2011

- Researched search performance data and implemented findings into various ACS web properties via metadata implementation
- Updated and analyzed monthly reports on the search performance of ACS sites
- Gained a working knowledge of the ACS content management system and used it to update content including homepage images

Eclipse Web Media Norcross, GA

Search Engine Optimization Intern

August 2010 to December 2010

- Learned the fundamentals of search engine optimization (SEO) through rigorous training
- Researched keyword opportunities for various clients' websites and optimized newly created pages for those sites
- Developed skills in writing keyword-rich, search-optimized content

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA

Part-time UX/UI Design Bootcamp, Certification expected May 2020

University of Virginia, McIntire School of Commerce

Charlottesville, VA

- M.S. in Commerce, Concentration in Marketing and Management, Degree conferred August, 2012, GPA: 3.51/4.0
- Participated in a month-long global immersion experience visiting numerous companies across Europe in Summer 2012

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA

- B.S. in Computational Media, Minor in Spanish, Degree conferred May, 2011, GPA: 3.72/4.0
- Participated in the Italian Film Studies program involving four weeks of international study in Gorizia, Italy in 2008

SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS

Certifications: Salesforce Certified Administrator, Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder

Software Development: Extensive experience with requirements gathering, user story writing, test case creation, and testing execution. Extensive knowledge of Agile methodology and experience working on Agile teams

Software / Products: Salesforce (certified with extensive project experience), JIRA (extensive project experience), HP-ALM (project experience), ALMComplete (project experience), Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint - extensive project experience), SQLDeveloper (project experience), Quintiq planning software (project experience), Google Analytics (training only), SPSS (training only), Adobe suite (XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, Flash, After Effects - training only)

Web Development: Basic knowledge of XHTML, CSS, and web standards

Video Production: Experience filming and experience editing in Final Cut Pro and After Effects

Search Marketing: Exposure and basic knowledge of search engine optimization and search marketing including use of Google Analytics and Adobe Omniture

Programming: Professional experience writing SQL queries. Class experience with Java, Python, C, Processing

Foreign Language: Spanish – Moderate reading and writing fluency

ACTIVITIES & AWARDS

Connect with Tech Host 2010-2011: Hosted multiple high school students as a part of a Georgia Tech recruitment program **LeaderShape Participant** 2010: Participated in prestigious weeklong leadership conference

Kappa Sigma Scholarship Chair 2010: Supervised the scholarship efforts of the chapter and administered study sessions **Kappa Sigma Leadership Chair** 2009: Sought out and encouraged membership in clubs and leadership positions on campus